all right so you work for a big company
you have a lot of people that are
writing go code and you're using
something like GitHub Enterprise cloud
and you're using inner Source philosophy
so everybody in your company is is
creating things and they're being able
to build they're being able to build
their projects or go apps or command
line tools or apis or everything during
using GitHub actions uh cicd that have
dependencies on all of these effectively
private repos that on your inner Source
perhaps they're all in the same
organization probably not though if
you're doing inner Source get up
interprise Cloud you probably have stuff
all over the place right you got like
maybe four or five organizations and
then you figured out some naming
convention to use for all the repos that
are being placed in there there and then
everybody in your company is being you
know dumped into those organizations in
order to see everything within that that
um if that describes your scenario this
video is for you um how do you create
the most effective the most easy to
maintain um architecture and best
practice and policy for building and
releasing your go applications
using uh GitHub actions GitHub workflow
actions whatever you want to call them
how do you do that and particularly you
know using something like go releaser
which is got a standard action um you
wouldn't have to build your own Runners
Runners are containers that that that
Implement get of action um there's a lot
of stuff there and there might be some
things for you to unpack and go research
before you continue with this video so
pause the video if you didn't understand
everything I just said um but if you are
there and you might be stuck you might
be stuck wondering how am I going to
build this you know this critical in our
case like you know K login to log into
all these machines we have all of the
credentials and login um business logic
is built into a single binary that
distribute to our internal people
because we do on Prem kubernetes um in
addition to gcp and other things so so
that's one one example that's that's a
simple one we're going to use that
simple case study or use case to go
through the different options about what
you would have to do we're not going to
be showing any code here we're just
going to be talking about five possible
approaches to getting this to work and
opening up this topic for debate in the
threads because we there's been a lot of
feedback from a lot of really capable
Prof professionals uh since I did this
since I started talking about this stuff
and researching it so we're going to try
to summarize that today um okay so the
the first case study is I just want to
build a single binary with a private you
know thing with no dependencies but I
want to be able to push my release okay
that's that's one that's one recipe the
second one is I want to be able to build
uh an an API that has dependencies on
one or more other modules
um we're assuming a poly you know repo
organization as God intended God being
Rob Pike and the rest of the people over
at go monor repos are an Abomination
that should never be used in go and if
you need to fight me on that we'll do
that in another thread in another video
if you are using I don't care if you're
Google if you are trying to twist Go's
arm into a monor repo architecture when
it is fundamentally built on semantic
versioning per repo then you and you've
got scripts that are removing and adding
replace directives in your Goa file
another video for that another massive
rant about that coming I don't have that
done yet because it's going to make my
blood pressure shoot through the roof
just don't do it okay anyway so we're
assuming a lot of modules so you say you
have when I say you have a lot of
modules I also am saying you have a lot
of repos so you have three or four repo
dependencies and they are all on your
GitHub Enterprise cloud in your Source
you know organization one or more
organizations right now the first thing
you have to know about this you probably
already know this is is you now have
everything is now private and as far as
go is concerned everything is now
private and this is the
biggest I I want to say that this is one
of the biggest
um I don't know if I want to say
shortsighted uh examples of
shortsightedness on go I the go module
system was clearly built on git and it
was clearly built on the assumption that
everything's going to be public and then
Along Comes you know this inner Source
philosophy where we're you know we're a
closed organization but we're open
inside that's inner source and and you
have a problem because now unless you're
do you're using on Prem you know
Enterprise server ghe versus
ghec now when you have a server on Prem
you're to go because every you're you're
on a bpn everything is effectively p uh
public go doesn't care where you go for
that kind of stuff and it works fine
because everything's public as far as go
is concerned but as soon as you you move
over to the Enterprise Cloud thing now
you're you're private effectively so you
have a problem you can't build anything
anymore uh you might know about go
private and being able to build things
so so now i' I've talked about the
scenarios and we're going to talk about
five ways
to address this problem and and I to
tell you the truth I'm only recently
coming to understanding so if you know
more about them please let us know um
the the first one the GitHub runner in
NRC is eh that is that is a pat that's a
pat that's a pat option you got to put
the token in there it's got to be a pat
so the the first one is is is probably
the one that will come to most people's
minds and that's the deployment key um
deployment keys are deployment keys are
designed just exactly like they say for
building dependencies on a specific
repo um and as I understand it
deployment keys are added to repos only
which means that if you added a deploma
key to a repo anything that used that
repo would have to have the deploma key
deployment keys are secrets means you
only see at one time which means you
have to have some way to some place to
put the secret like in Vault or
something because once you see it I
don't I don't even remember the
expiration dates and timelines on the
deployment keys but it it's isolated
scope but they're also they're uh
they're already they already have readon
so in that sense they're simpler than
Pat personal access tokens but they are
you know they're very very simple and
they're per repo which means that um in
order to build uh cicd action as far as
I know I could be wrong on this um with
a dependency on that thing your cic
actions would have to potentially do
different things to be able to talk to
the different repos um somebody
suggested perhaps a deployment keeper an
organization I've never seen that I
don't know that that can be done um that
would be something to worth worth
looking at but but before we go down the
path about whether you add uh a token or
a credential or something to to a repo
let's let's talk about that so there's
actually three places that you can add
credentials you can add credentials to
the repo right to the GitHub repo um you
can add credentials to a user and you
can add the credent well there's four
actually and you can add the credentials
to to an
organization and there's one more you
can add the credentials to a GitHub app
okay so we're going to talk about apps
last or second to last so those are the
places where you would add your
credentials so when you're trying to
think about well where am I even storing
these credentials and who's getting them
and how am I going to manage them that's
a big question because depending on how
you
deployed um your inner Source
architecture for your developers um you
know you could have you could have a
thousand people in one organization and
it would make a lot of sense to just add
a credential to the
organization but you may be dealing as
we are with a with a team that is not
keen a security team that's not keen on
adding a secret to an entire
organization right now from a practicals
perspective everything that's building
any cic that's using that secret whether
it's any of the options we're going to
talk about
you know you you got the issue of is it
going to expire what happens if it you
have to renew it does everybody have to
change their actions to use the new one
if it's an or if it's an organizational
secret it usually is going to be a lot
easier to manage um however however and
this I want to put this out for
consideration in our
organization it is not easy to deal with
the people who manage the organization
and we have I I don't like saying that
way I'm trying to be politically correct
but it is practically impossible to get
them to to do a secret and if I if I
were going to have the organiz have them
modify an
organization um it would be you know
they would have to they would have to we
would first of all we have to get them
to do it and they're already overworked
and if they're managing all kinds of
different things for a different
organization and and they haven't really
come up with a with a strategy of
creating uh a a cross org um credential
or secret of some kind that could be
used in any cicd uh in any repo across
the Enterprise um these are Dev opsy G
opsy kind of topics that are more GitHub
related but the the main point I'm
trying to make is that the number one
consideration for which of these
Solutions you pick for us is going to be
how easy for us is it to to maintain it
am I going to not be able to do a
release until I get somebody to update a
thing you know whatever that thing is uh
am I going to you know how much
management am I going to have to depend
on from others versus doing it myself
and this is a big deal if you're inside
of an
organization um that that has to fight
with all these kind of kind of
situations all the time um and I you
know no dirty laundry here but let's
just say there's there's you know
there's constant Dynamics we'll say
between the security team the GitHub
team um I I don't mind saying saying
that this this corporate initiative to
to to to migrate to Inner Source has
been completely derailed and dozens if
not hundreds of of organizations and
projects are now asking when is it going
to come back because there's a
disagreement between the GitHub team on
in our case who it's not GitHub corpor
our internal who deployed our our
architectural solution and the security
team and so the security came came to
them and said oh no you don't and they
halted the entire migration effort for
the whole freaking company and so having
I I don't mind sharing that little bit
of dirty laundry with you
because if you are in this situation the
reason that I am running this down the
reason I'm making this video is because
there's a good chance that one of you is
going to find the way that you think is
best for you and it's not going to jive
with what your Enterprise want and you
are going to need to
articulate these options these five
different options so that when it comes
time to either defend your position or
tell them suggest a new position you
need to say look I here's the work I've
done I've gone through this and here are
options and this is why I consider this
the best option because you're probably
going to have to make your case the
chance of the people actually doing
deployment even knowing what these
options are is is not entirely 100%
let's put it that way um uh
okay so here let's let's having done
that so you have we know a few things
are going to have to happen right in
order for our cc cicd to work with
private repos we're going to have to add
login essentially essentially login
credentials we that's a broad term on
purpose we're going to have to add login
we have to get it so that our cicd
that's running our action our runner has
permission to see these repos and how do
we give it permission well we either
give it the permissions of you know a
single user uh as a user and create a
generic user right we can think of this
problem in terms of like well how would
we solve this problem if we had a person
doing this and that's a very good way to
think of it there are some you know so
we can think of it as like creating a
generic user ID how would we you know
and then give that generic user ID
membership in the org etc etc we'll come
back to that we have we have the aidea
of using an existing user or an existing
organization and create a credential for
that user or that organization that
spans the organization or the user or
everything that that existing user has
access to probably a bad idea to do that
for an existing user because what
happens if that user goes away right the
other thing too is perhaps an existing
user has right access to some repos
maybe we don't want that maybe we want
our generic user to only have read
access to all these repos right and then
we have and that can be done through Pat
or SSH and we'll get to that so now and
then you have you know you have this
GitHub app id idea and the GitHub app
idea um is you know you associate all
the same things with the app but then
the app can be registered to and owned
by a specific user uh or
organization uh I'm going you spoiler
alert I think it's it's too much work to
do that a lot of people do that it's
kind of the standard thing that people
suggest I'm like why and I'm going to
I'm going to justify that conclusion and
then there's the deployment Keys
deployment keys are access to a specific
repo as far as I know so so let's let's
let's go back to our problem right um so
I I pretty much already outlined all the
different ways to do this uh except for
one um and so let's just talk about that
now if you are and we'll review I
promise we'll review all this you you
another thing that I have not tried yet
um is to set up a proxy and what you do
is you set up a you set up a uh
basically a your own GitHub using git
gitlab something like that internally
and you put you you have a you you store
your repos there and and then you use a
proxy you use go proxy instead of
everything else and then anybody that
wants to release anything in your
internal go environment um is is
publishing it
to this go proxy server um that has been
recommended to me recently uh some of
the larger organizations that are
working with go uh do that apparently
using that and then just using HTTP you
know um stuff is is well you wouldn't
even need it because internally within
your VPN you'd be able to get to all
you're basically not using GitHub right
for your cicd in that case I mean you
are and you you you you all You' have to
do is make sure that you're network
connection from your GitHub is able to
talk to your inner uh Network which
pretty much every organization that's
doing this kind of stuff has already
worked that out um we regularly deploy
two kubernetes internally from inner
Source on GitHub um and that that so
good chance that the cicd that's running
an inner Source on GitHub will have
access to internal servers um and
apparently the go proxy setting up a go
proxy to put all of the go project that
matter uh is is the way to do that but
this does not get around the problem
okay well how do you authenticate what
goes on the go proxy who has access to
the go proxy to upload uh go modules um
is somebody is somebody within the
company going to gatekeep what gets put
on the go proxy um there's there are a
ton of considerations for the whole go
proxy idea um and that's really all I'm
going to talk about it because I don't
know a lot about it I haven't used it
before I know that it's a thing um it's
really important that you know about it
though we're going to come back to the
other four that being number five um
it's important that you know about it
though because there's a good chance
that when your internal go you know
Center of whatever Excellence or
something gets a hold of what you're
doing and you know there's there's an
architectural decision at the highest
point there's a good chance that the go
team at some at some level is going to
interject and say the one best way to do
this the best practice is for us to set
up a proxy for the whole entire company
you can't release a go thing at all
unless you put it on our go proxy and
they will there's a good chance that
they will want to do that once they find
out about it because it it is it does
seem like it's one of the best ways to
have a solution that's you know for your
entire organization but then you have
like siloed organizations fighting over
whose proxy you're going to use um you
know you you got you got a lot of other
considerations about that and so um but
I think you probably need to be aware of
it because it may be that some companies
want you to go that way uh whether or
not they force you to do it or not is a
separate question um and I you know we
haven't hit we haven't got that far
along um at least in at least I as far
as I know okay so let's talk about the
other four options um and they are the
deployment Keys uh the the personal
access tokens the SSH keys and the
GitHub app uh installation token option
uh deployment keys are per repo as we
said and that means that you have to add
a deployment key and you have to keep
track of it outside of GitHub because
you can never see it again after you
make one you can pretty much just rule
them out they're not realistic they're
not realistic because the number of the
the management of the key is so
problematic that in order to have
multiple projects dependent on one
package they'd all have to have
deployment keys so they have to share
the deployment key and if the deployment
key changed they'd have to make sure
they get this a new one which means
you'd have to have some external you
know storage for that that's pulling it
in like Vault and then have a vault
secret and then have that pull it's just
complicated and unnecessary it's like
crazy so just don't even try to ply keys
in my opinion um the second the second
one uh is personal access tokens and
right now I'm just going to tell you
right now I am struggling to decide
between personal access tokens and SSH
keys and I'll tell you why um
so let's let's rule out GitHub um let's
just let's rule out number four let's
rule out GitHub uh application tokens
okay um they're very precisely they're
called GitHub application installation
tokens if you hear somebody say GitHub
app tokens it's probably what they mean
and as far as I can tell from all the
documentation on GitHub um this was
recommended to me relatively recently
our GitHub team recommended this to us
as well and I'm just going to tell you
right now it's not worth it and the the
main reason people site is because it
has a higher rate limit than other
things this is the official way to Grant
access to things and I'm like I why do
you need a higher rate limit for a cicd
release I already said this today in
this video but so the the the the
process of getting a GitHub application
token is you have to get a GitHub app
GitHub apps are designed to solve a much
bigger wider scope of a problem than
just giving you access to your go
private repos in fact that that is like
a tiny little fractional piece of what
you can do with GitHub apps the GitHub
GitHub app lets you talk to the API and
do literally anything and you can make
some pretty amazing things with that and
they have advanced rate limiting on how
many times you hit the API enough none
of that matters you just want to build
your app you just want access to your
private repo so you can build your app
so the first thing you're going to
notice when you go look at the GitHub
app stuff is you're going to be
overwhelmed with the unnecessary
documentation even to just do the test
you have to set up like a a proxy you
have to set up a a proxy ooth you know
thing just to even test how to create a
app when really all you really want is
that one token and so the the the
process is you know register an app
under an organization or a user that has
to own it which means you have to have a
user and organization already that means
you're already in the same you know mess
with like talking to someone to say hey
we need to have you add a new you know a
new app to our to to our GitHub
organization William why don't you add
them have them just add you know private
key or something instead so you already
got that same problem right but in
addition to that now you have to manage
you know this pen file and everything in
the app in order to get it so you've got
this UN in my opinion you've got this
unnecessary layer of complication
between between you know giving a
credential to an or or a user in order
to build repos that they own and or
repos from from places that they own so
I I think the app thing is is is bogus
and someone correct me if you're wrong
if you disagree I don't understand where
this is coming from I I keep hearing it
as like that's the only way to truly do
you know go build go private repos and I
personally think that the reason that
that's coming that way at me is because
people are used to doing this to build
other projects and they're not go
projects or they whatever right and so
it I think people are defaulting to it
when it it it may not be the simplest
solution for go let me talk about what
the simplest Solutions are um let's talk
about the one that's that's that's kind
of obvious
um you set up a generic user this is
going to be the easiest to get your head
around because it's already the same
thing you do all the time the the
easiest one to do to get your head
around is to create a generic ID right
you create a generic ID that's an ID
that's that's that's not directly it's
owned that and it's a member of an
organization or that has visibility to
all of the repos that it ever could need
to be more most of the time that's going
to mean that that that that generic user
is a member of an organization and you'd
have to flag it you'd have to track it
You' have to see if your you know your
your your whatever your um identity
management people are going to be okay
with you creating a generic ID some
organizations have already got the
architectural policy in place uh for
using generic IDs for multiple things um
whether it be a kubernetes ID or
something they create a generic ID and
you know it's an application ID
essentially and then they they they
allow multiple people to administer that
that user
um and to you know do things with that
user and even though it's a team it's
not necessarily it's a group it's I'm
calling it a generic ID some people call
it a pseudo pseudo ID pseudo user I
avoid the term pseudo user because
somebody thought I actually meant pseudo
suo when I was saying it so I say
generic uh account so you have a generic
account everybody knows that that
generic account has you know is going to
have limited access to things um but by
default it doesn't it's no different
than any other user account and you can
see how this is really easy to get your
head around right all you're really
doing is it's like you pretend like you
got an intern on the team and their job
is to to do all the builds it's really
easy to think about because and to
manage in that sense you're like okay we
created a user account and that that
user all they're going to do is they
just we're just going to give them read
access to anything because we're
terrified of
them we don't we don't want them to have
right access because you know they might
commit you know a URL Local Host Coen
880 um you know in one of the else which
happened not in our company I thought
that was amazing we just we do not want
the internet right access right we just
want the intern to do the builds and put
our releases out there so we give we
create this generic inter kind of
account we give them only read access so
they're as far as I mean they have full
they have full access to their own stuff
but when it comes time to you know give
them access to other stuff in the
organization we only give them
collaborator read access to the specific
repos that they need to see um and
there's two ways to do this right you
can manage the the access uh in terms of
the organization they have full access
to the whole organization or we could
say you really don't have access to
anything and then we could have people
Grant collaborator access to that user
uh in readon mode for the projects that
they need um this is this is a this is
it's this feels like user management
more than anything else because because
if you if you take that approach it's
you know you're you're literally
approaching it like a user how does that
user than authenticate well just like
anything else right you can set them you
can any any way that that user would
authenticate in a cicd action can is is
good is good right so you would still
the easiest one is to set up SSH or
https with a pat you know however you
want to do it um and then you know that
can access that the cicd can access
anything that that user could access
right and then you manage access to the
different projects by the collaborator
or the organizational membership and
that's that's how you do it that that is
the my opinion that's the easiest we may
end up going that way but we're we're
kind of on the fence between that and
this last way and I'll make this the
last one
um the the last one is um personal
access tokens so and we talked about
them before I'm going to talk about them
again so a personal access token is the
way that a user uh would authenticate
right you go out get a personal access
token plop it into your GitHub command
line tool and boom your GitHub command
line tool now has access to do anything
that you would do and with R to get him
it's the same exact thing uh in fact
it's almost exactly the same as an SSH
key the only difference is that with a
personal access token you can itemize
and you can you know you can really get
precise with what that specific token is
granting access for on behalf of the
user or org that owns the personal
access token um if you by the way if you
don't want to do I mean you can add a
personal access token to an org and then
you know any any user but then you still
have to have you still have to have um
uh a repo that's got a C cicd process
that's going to you know invoke the
personal access token of the org um so
whether you put the the these thing you
can't ssh in as an or as far as I know
as far as I know I don't think you can
identify yourself and log in as an org
um I could I could be wrong on that
actually okay does anybody know I
haven't done that in a long time I I
haven't logged in as I've always logged
in as me and then i' I've been able to
do stuff as my org uh because I'm an
administrator on the org I'm pretty sure
you can't do anyway so so I think it
comes down to creating um either a
personal access token or an SSH key um
both of those by the way have to be
stored outside because the personal
access token you get it once and it goes
away and it expires in 180 days maximum
um you have to refresh it all the time
in fact let's talk about the personal
access token versus SSH approach um a
little bit um so the SSH tokens do not
expire you you they're designed to not
expire you'd have to set them up to
expire on your own um
that means that when you add one you
know it's good until you revoke it right
um and if you are going to be change any
any
project that is going to have cicd
that's going to log in as that user um
is going to need to access that secret
now as long as they're you shouldn't
because it's just the one user you don't
you probably aren't going to have to
mess mess with the secrets in each of
the projects because it's you know it's
this it's the one secret for that user
and you're logging in as that user so
you shouldn't have to do that but if you
are still paranoid about that you could
still put the SSH private key in a you
know of Vault secret and then create an
action that pulls it in um and and none
of your projects would be impacted by
that because they don't have to they you
know if you change if if if if you're
Secret Gets compromised with something
you just change it change it in Vault
and everybody gets a new one um I mean
there's still the question of how do you
authenticate to Vault you've got the
secret that's authenticating the Vault
how is that any better policy-wise um
and the consideration with secure shell
is is it even okay for your organization
to have a non-expiring secret in you
know in the system and I think the
answer is yes because if you had a user
if you had a again back to this intern
idea the inter
is not going to have to refresh their
SSH key all the time maybe they need to
be I I I'm pretty sure you can't do that
but um you know personal access tokens
definitely can be set to expire I mean
they have to be right but if you're
setting up an SSH key that's they're
they're they're by Nature they're
designed to work all the time so as long
as you protect the key the private key
um then you know you you don't have the
hassle of of dealing with the keys is
that less secure is it going to pass
your security policy that's that's up to
you to decide and by the way that's with
using SSH is just one solid um
connection to that and it's the the the
granularity of access is then managed as
if it was being granted to the user I
think I've said that 10 times now but
it's really important um the personal
access token thing is giving access um
to that user but only to some things
that the user can do and this is where I
think personal access tokens are going
to be the preference uh without without
a doubt the the most common
documentation about how to do this is
using personal access tokens uh
specifically and go using the netrc file
um there are a lot of people who have
tried to build in the token into the URL
and used and modify their G config file
um and I can tell you that the standard
go way to do that is to use netrc
instead of that um you can definitely
get it to work that way but you know
populating the NRC file with the
credentials the pat um is the you know
that's that's the easiest way to do it
um if you're going to use the SSH way um
you have to do a go get config um line
in your cicd action to change it because
it's not going to use SSH and I got the
thing about SSH that's a little hard to
consider is for some reason it feels
like when you're using SSH as as
described you're kind of swimming
Upstream because it seems like a lot of
the the the documentation a lot of the
stuff about using actions and stuff is
all is all based on htps authentication
um using the tokens in fact um you know
you can use the GitHub token the one
that just goes per repo per run uh
anywhere I mean you can use it in in you
know the get address so you can put that
in NRC um and you know there's just a
lot of you know the use of a token is
pretty prevalent throughout all the
examples and I I tend to think that
um the personal access tokens are the
way to go um the fundamental difference
between a personal access token and SSH
token as far as I'm concerned is that
the SSH token does not expire and the
personal access token must expire Ever
every 180 days um that is a everything
else kind of comes down to that because
in terms of scope and access and
everything I feel I feel like that now
the again if you're using a generic ID
which you should be in this case right
then the scope of access that is granted
through you know uh itemized personal
access token is less important because
you know the user unless unless your
organization is incapable of adding a
generic user uh with limited access to
other
repos and that's the thing I'm
researching right now it's very possible
that you can't do that it's like if you
add a user and it's in your org it gets
the same terms as everybody El else in
the org including right access to repos
that it shouldn't have right that would
be a solid case to go the personal
access token route because at that point
the personal access token route is
granted with that user but then the
access token itself can limit access for
that token in fact you could have
several personal access tokens uh for a
generic account that have that have
different scoped access and you can put
those in your secrets management system
and you could pull those out but you
better be am sure to set up alerts and
stuff because when those things expire
your entire CDs process is broke and
that is a consideration that's very uh
it's weighing very heavily on me and my
team right now um if you sign up if you
sign up for personal access token
approach that you are signing up for
credential management and certificate
renewal all the time and then you need
to make sure that you do that because if
that if if it expires I mean there's
nothing that will make a senior manager
a senior executive architect come down
on your team harder than having outage
is because you let your searchs
expire because it's so embarrassing it's
one of the most embarrassing things a
senior a senior you know architect or
director can have their team do and it
happens all the time I cannot tell you
how many times we've had critical multi
thousand outages because Sears expired
and nobody knew they were coming up in
next
expiration so you know it could be that
your security policy says Thou shalt
expire everything all the time um and
you don't have the choice and that
choice has already been made if that's
if that's the case Pat is your only
option it literally is your only option
Pat or GI up app tokens if you want to
go through that hassle but it's you know
it's no no better it's really it's
literally no better the only time you
would ever use a gith up app token is if
you wanted to do something else besides
just build your go project like you you
you wanted to to build some sort of
integration that that that regularly hit
the API to do other things which I don't
um and and so so that decision may
already been made for you if if instead
your your team is fine with stuff having
non-expiring credentials U and they
would rather not be reminded of of of
logging credentials all the time then
the SSH key and the generic user account
seems to make um a good approach hi
everybody um I really feel that's been a
long uh a long video so at the end of it
let's just summarize the five ways that
you can build go uh you can build
internal project go projects from
private slin Source repos uh the first
one is try to figure out a way to get a
deployment key for every repo and
everything that needs it and make sure
that the build the build actions know
about it very problematic almost nobody
even recommends it uh the second one is
personal access token spine grain
control associated with either an
organization if you can pull it off or a
user in our case it's easier to request
a user than it is to
request um a personal access token on a
repo for an entire I mean for an
organization so so re again organization
or or or user generic user uh the third
one is an SSH token uh an SSH generic
account um and that is only for a
generic account I'm pretty sure you
can't have SSH login for an organization
it would have to be two yet you know a
generic account I guess I guess I
realize there's a distinction there
between personal access token and SSH a
personal access token can be added to a
repo I mean to a to an
organization uh both an SSH uh private
key and a personal access token can be
added to a generic user but the SSH key
I believe cannot be added associated
with an organization help me if I got
that wrong
um but let me know um the fourth way is
is is people talk about it all the time
and that's GitHub uh GitHub apps and
specifically using the installation
token from a GitHub app to do the login
uh GitHub apps are bloated and and well
well beyond the scope of just wanting to
be able to get access to build um
they're problematic and they everybody
recommends them but I think they're crap
personally and the the the last option
is setting up a go proxy
uh which forces your entire organization
to put everything on the proxy and that
that bypasses all of the inner source
security um that is necessary for all of
the options that have an organization or
or an owner Associated that we talked
about the other four so if if you are
indeed you know if you if you are indeed
wanting to gatekeep all the go in your
organization a proxy does sound like one
of the better options but but again
there's the internal dynamics of of that
and what that looks like um to be fair
as I said before I have never set up a
go proxy to do those things uh I don't
know what it takes to do that I don't
know what commitment in terms of
infrastructure resources and internal
management is required to do that um a
lot of the people that are going the GH
you know Enterprise Cloud option within
her Source they're doing it because they
want to Outsource all of that management
and hassle so the idea of of keeping a
proxy behind inside behind the you know
VPN firewall um seems kind of
counter uh productive to the goals of
using an inner Source how hosted in
GitHub Cloud it seems like they're kind
of against I mean if you're going to do
that why not just host GitHub internally
on a GitHub Enterprise server right and
they you got you address the same
problem um and you know these these
issues are are coming up they're pretty
big issues because go unlike anything
else is impacted by these migrations
because go is fundamentally the go
module system is f fundamentally tied to
the git addresses of the packages so as
you migrate from Enterprise server or
whatever it is you're using to
Enterprise inner Source Cloud sorts of
things you already have to touch every
one of your packages every single one
has to be changed at the very least it
has to have its new Module location
changed this means you got to think
about things like like like like naming
and and who's going to own it and and
where how the issues get resolved and
where are we going to release it these
are big big issues and just knowing what
the direction is and whether how cicd is
even going to work is a decision I would
think you would want to decide well in
advance of of of of signing up on the
DOA line and saying you're going to go
with an inner Source get up Enterprise
Cloud solution because you are depending
on how dependent you are on go you have
fundamentally dictated
you know a lot of instant work to do the
migration to get that stuff over there
and once you go there you you can't go
back no pun intended if you go back
you're going to be breaking everything
you're going to have to re-release
everything this is for better or worse
this is a reality with go go
fundamentally depends internally within
the language within the language itself
depends on how stuff is organized in in
the you know the the git architecture
the git repo um solution that you've
decided and if you mess with that you're
talking to every single time you mess
with it you're talking about a lot of
work to move it even if it's minimally
just rebuilding and making sure all your
systems working and making sure all the
names got changed and I I I I feel like
the people some of the senior Architects
are making decisions about um
architectural Direction with in the
company and business decisions are not
fun they're not fully aware of the
impact to the go to to projects
implemented and go because they they're
coming from Another Universe they're
coming from like the Pearl cpan universe
or npm or something like that where
there's already a centralized solution
and it's just a matter of granting
access to that same server and you're
good to go that is not the case for go
when you move stuff and go you have to
deal with it and you don't want people
fussing around with replace directives
and all the stuff that they have to do
to make that work so please you know
please give this this these thoughts
some consideration i' love to have your
feedback in the chat below I'm going to
stop talking now give my voice arrest
that was quite a b a bit um but thank
you thank you again for uh all your
feedback um if I miss something
glaringly obvious um I would really
really
appreciate um oh hey Amic how you doing
I'd really um really really appreciate
your your feedback um in the comment
section of YouTube here uh so other
people can find it with this video um or
in you know our Discord if you want you
can come on in twitch and do that we're
going to go back to co-working that's
not really a rant but hopefully that'll
that'll give some some some structure to
the decision making that you have to
make you got to pick one i' i' I've run
this by several people and that's it
those that those are the only options so
you got to pick one